Hello everyone and welcome
Come to our open pie Excel course
That's right in this course we're going to learn how to automate
Via python going to use
The number one
Popular python Library open pie Excel
Order to automate
A common
Felt hats and build lots of projects along the way
In this lecture we're doing overview of all of the topics
In this course
Starting with the first
For topics we're going to do an introduction.
How to use
Who's open pie
And how to
Run
Python on the web
How to automate
From the web
You don't have to download or install anything
And after that we are going to learn how to build worksheet
Falling. We're going to learn how to format cells
Via open Pikesville
I'm going to learn how to build 2D charts programmatically
Taking our data and visualizing it
Programmatically
I forgot to go to build a project together
Build an employee time on that allows employees to
Register their work hours
Immediately
It's an automated format where you generate
A new timelog every
Hey.
Learn how to write data to a text file
How to take an Excel sheet
Add
Using programming using Python Programming how to write it to a text file or any file that you want really
How to update a spreadsheet
He programmatically chart type
In Section 8
Build more charts programmatically
And finally infection 9 we would learn how to scrape a webpage and get data that we want and save it
Twin Excel file
Who's going to save you a lot of time a lot of energy this entire course is going to teach you
How to speed up your business processes
How to automate
Common tasks
And
How to build useful projects
You'll find yourself using
On the job
Thank you all for watching I will see you
In the next lecture we're going to learn how
We can run
Python
And run over projects on the web without installing any
I'll see you in the next life