Hello everyone and welcome back to our open pie Excel course
And that's what you're going to learn how we can run our python code
Automate
RXL
Sheetz
All via the web with no downloading or installing
Required
Only have to do is navigate to collab
Doc's research. Google
This is a free website
That Google has developed to allow you to run python
On the web
That means that any code that we type into a new Google colab file
She's very similar to a Google doc
File or a Google Sheets file
Any code that we run in here that is python code
The Google colab compiler is going to automatically run it for us to fight.
That means we don't have to download or install python for this
Of course we can
Manipulate our Excel files
Via Google colab
Now if you want to download and install python you can of course and you
Run the code
That we show you in Thai charm or
Any other editor that you want
Or you can
Skip seat installing and downloading and just
Google colab
All of your files are going to be
To Google Drive
Via Google colab
All right and that is how
We are going to run open Tai Excel and how we're going to automate Excel via the web
Let's get started
With our next
Lecture we're going to jump into
Are section on
Common fundamental tasks
With open Kayak cell
I will see you in the next