Hello everyone and welcome back to our open pie Excel course
Fletcher we're going to learn how to make a new workbook using open pie Excel let's be
Begin by importing from open Kayak until we're going to import the workbook
It will allow us to create a new workbook to create a new workbook we first declarative
Variable
Such as w b typically that's the name for a workbook and we initialise the variable to contain
And initialization of the workbook object that means that we are instantiating
A workbook class to create a new workbook after this we're going to make a destiny
Nation filename weenie to make a name for the South we want to save this destination
Underscore
File name and inside of quotation marks we can put the name of any
You workbook name we want such as for example
New workbook
We also have to add the file extension. Xlsx in his case the
Standard Excel file after we have created the file we can then make
A new workbook
And we can make a worksheet
We're going to do is add a new line to make a new workbook in or
Order to make a new workbook we're going to first make another variable
We'll call this
W
Which stands for worksheet and you can use longer names as well but typically we will
Use these initializers
And going to initialize WS2 equal w b
. active this means that we're taking the active workbook
Signing into two equal
Bws
Variable for science value to the Ws
Variable
After this weekend then
Make a title for our worksheet
Let's do that
We're going to call WSDOT title to set a title property of our active workbook
We're going to call this
Our
New
Active workbook
I just like that we have made a workbook out after we have maybe workbook we can
Then go ahead and populate it with values let's go ahead and we'll do that next
We can populate
Rows and columns inside of this workbook all via
Open pie Excel
For example we can Loop through for row in a range of
Rose pictures from 1 to 10
We can go ahead and sign WS
Got a pen
This is going to upend a new value and we can also State the range that we want to append it from
Such as 100
This is going to upend a new value
Into our range from Rose 12-row 10
Let's take a look at how we can make
Another worksheet inside of our workbook
Where.
We can go ahead and
Use the create sheet method
For example we can call this our
W
Sheetz
We can call this equal
Are workbook.
Create sheets
In the parentheses of the crate sheet method we're going to set the title of our new
What's back here
Let's call this number two
Ozium AB you can see all that
Now we can set the values of our WS sheet
What's a sign
It's
Value at a specific location in order to populate a specific cell
In single quotation marks you're going to put in some value for zeppoles want to populate
The column A
Andro 5
Then you'll add a 5in to the quotation marks
Then after the equal sign you're going to put in some value
Put in some value here
That means going to put in some value here
Into the A5 cell
Let's go ahead and test out the code that we just made
For example what if I wanted to
Get the value of wst
At the sell A5
Well I have to do is type in that line WS sheets
At 85
Followed by the dot value property
What do you think is going to appear when I hit run
We'll look at that we have some value here being printed out
Because that is the value of
My cell A5
In the Ws sheet
And if you remove the dot value
And you just type in WS sheet at
A5
And you hit run
They'll notice you have being printed out
Cell number 2.85
That's because
Google call abisai do you know that the variable
Refers to a cell in the number two
Sheetz
Got a five
Referring to that sell in this sheet
Number two
That means we successfully made a sheet called WS sheet
Inside of our workbook using the create sheet method
And we successfully populated Excel
With the value of some value here
You can also text this out
Bye
Getting WS
And getting
One of the values inside of
Gyros in the range 1
Depend
Let's try that out we're going to go ahead and call WS
And let's get for example a two
Go to call. Value on WS
And here we have zero
Being printed out
Let's try for example
Instead of B2
This time we have one being logs and B2
If we have C2
Now we have to
Being printed out as the Value Inn
That's lc2
Let's try C3 and see the values going to be too as well
That is inside of
Our first worksheet at the cell
C3
Let's build out
One more worksheet
To really test all this out
For that we're going to go ahead and we'll make another worksheet with colvis and another
Worksheet will call artwork book
. create sheet
Function
And inside of the
Parentheses here you will call me after put in the title
The title is going to be the title of a sheet so it's called this
Third sheet
Just like that
Then we can populate values of our third sheet
For example we can go for each row
In the range of
Adamson go freeze column in the range of
Chew
We can populate some values
For example we could populate
The values
At another
Worksheet
. cell
And here we can populate values such as you can set the column
Sequel to call
The road to equal zero whatever at
And the values equal a formatted string
Hand with
Wrap.in double quotation marks cure
What we can do is format a
String hair to place in the
Value act that sell
For example we can call. Format
Get
Column
Letter
The current column
Get column letter is another
Function that we can use
And I just want to separate these all in it
On a new line so that you can all see him
Alright just like that
This means that at every cell in our range
Which were making with raid
Nested for Loop
We're going to
Display
The column letter of the current column
Now we actually have to import
Get calm letter
Because that is an open pie Excel
Function
So at the top of your file here hit enter and import
Open
From
Open pie XL. Utils
Import guest column letter
This is going to import just this one function that we can use
From open Pikesville
Nativities
Now that we've imported that function is going to be valid and
We're going to be able to use it
So let's test that out
What we'll do is we're going to
Hit enter
And make sure that you're printing outside of
Your for loops
Nuevo print
Act another worksheets
I'm going to print out the value at any column such as be
B8
It's nice outgoing from column feet
But you notice that would be out of range from our range of 125 Swiss do instead 585
And want to print out its value
Before we hit run take a guess at what's the value you think is going to be printed out
Going to hit run
And see the results
Right now we have none
Being printed out
So let's try again something like B1 will hit run
And this time we have B
Printed out
That's because we're printing out
Akon letter
For every value in our row
Are going from
Rose
125 and columns 2210
If we try a one and we hit run
We're getting none because it's out of our range
We do see one and hit run
We have C
And that proves that we placed in the values only into this specific range