Hello everyone and welcome back to our open pie Excel course
And a sweatshirt we're going to learn how to save a workbook that we just
In order to save a workbook we're going to first of all call the workbook B name w b
And then we're going to call the save function
On the workbook
We're going to call
And inside of the parentheses we're going to put in the argument
This save function
And that argument is going to be the path
To defile
Do you want to save
For example if I'm going to save it in the default location on my computer then all I have to do is put in the name of the file
The name of my file is destination file name because that's the new workbook I created
And I stored that name in this variable destination file name
So I can copy that variable destination file name and paste it into
Be safe
Function
This is going to save
This file
It's new file to
My default location
Now if I want to save to a different location I have to put in the past before the founding
For example suppose I want to save
This workbook not to my computer but to Google Drive
What I can do is put in a path to Google Drive and then add the file name afterwards
Tactical Drive is Flash content / g-drive / my dry
And you just have to make sure you also add in a slash at the end
Because this is the path to the file
And then you also must add in the file name
Otherwise the state function won't know
How you want to save this file
It's brand new file
Everytime I run the code cell
This code is going to create a brand-new file
What the same name is it going to override the previous house was going to delete the old file if there is a file
Of this name is going to
Make a new
File
On top of that instead
And the file is always going to be called new underscore workbook
Got xlsx
Because that's what we called it
In this project
Now let's test this out if I want to see my file on Google Drive
Because this is not my
And not attack on my computer it's a pathan Google drive and I'm using Google
Collab
I have to import Google drive from Google colab
If you're following along with Google colab
And you want to stagedoor drive you also have to do that
With me
If you're following along
In a different editor liked itron than you won't have to
Save on Google Drive
And discuss the top of our file here
We are going to import Google Drive in order to save to it
We're going to from Google colab we're importing drive because that's where Drive exists
In our case
And we're going to call Dr. Amount this is going to mount
The past 2 Google Drive
Andy Pat is Flash contest V-drive
Just like this we can hit run on this code cell
Get a message to click on this link and enter an authorization code
And once you do that then you'll be able to
See this
File
Angel Google Drive
And we can click on this link enter the code
And that is what allowed was to
Now we're going to be saving files all throughout this course
So you'll get very good at it by the end