Hello everyone and welcome back door open Pikeville course
In this sweatshirt
To learn how to read a workbook via open pie Excel
That means that we already have a workbook somewhere in
Are computer or summer on Google Drive
And we want to read it get values
From it we are not making a new one
We're not writing one but we're reading one
Let's go ahead and learn how we can do that
First we have to import from open pie Excel
What is known as the load
Work
This is going to allow us to
Loda workbook
Now there are
Two different ways of loading a workbook
If your file is on your computer
Then you can go ahead and
Directly
Open up the workbook object
Which is going to be a new variable called w b
And we're going to assign a sequel
Vote underscore workbook
Now in parenthesis
You can put the path to your workbook
For example
The workbook is directly in my default path
But I can just call it by its name
Mark's doesn't matter
Will call the name of the workbook that we want to read such as new workbook. SL
Xlsx
Now this is
If there is no
File path for this is a file path in just add that
Before
Found him
Note that you must add the extension and also
Quotation marks around the name
The workbook that we created together in the previous lecture called new workbook.
Excel
SX
Now in the previous lecture we saved this workbook to our Google Drive
You can stay with your computer as well
But if you're using Google colab
And you're saving your workbooks to Google Drive
Then you have to read and port
Google drive into this project
For this if you're starting a brand new project here all we have to do
Is ad
That we want to import the drive
That means that from Google colab or going to import
Drive which represents Google Drive
Does only have to do this if you're following along with us in Google colab
As well to forget to call Dr. Mount amount function to
Mount on a past
Google Drive
And you do that with your past
Content / d Drive
This is how you can load
Files from Google Drive
And just ignore these two lines if you're just loading the work books from your computer instead
It is up to you
Alright so if you are
Loading the rock clock app from Google Drive
And what you like to do with add a file path
Before the final name
What we can do is we have to first of all call filename2 set
Argument
We have to put founding equals to tell python that we want to assign this value
To the filename argument
Now what we want to do is append
On
Our
Location of Google Drive
So we're going to open up
Quotation marks / contest 5G drive my drive
Flash don't forget that Final Flash
I'm just going to hit enter so you can
See all this on one line
Okay just hit enter again
I want you to go to see all this online okay
So here we have first the past
To defile
This is the package to put in for accessing any file on Google Drive
Anna this is a filename so together do add up to equally file path and the file name plus the file extension
You can replace the Google Drive path with the path on your computer
I just like that will be loading a workbook
It's important to put in the path exactly correctly without forgetting any forward flashes
Or else
Devote workbook
Function is not going to go to find
Dat file name exactly at that file path
Now this means we successfully loaded up our workbook
But how can we prove that
Well we can
Go ahead and grab one of the worksheets in the workbook
And print out one of its values so it's do that next
Polk County Jail
Is
Make another variable and we'll call this our sheets
Let's go ahead and get a seat inside of a rock book
Do a member from
Two letters ago we created
Some worksheets
For example we made 8/3
3rd Street
This is the name of
One of the worksheets in our workbook so we can call it
Just like this we call our workbook
Variable
And we're getting the third sheet
Which is the name of a sheet in
4:00
Now that we have saved is sheet inside of
A sheet variable
We can then
Print out one of
It's values
We can call the print function
To print
The sheets values at a certain cell
Just put in a cell
Increase marks
Four examples of CB-1
Solid B. Value property
Is it going to give us the value stored in
The B-1 cell
In the sheets
Variable which stores the third sheet
In our workbook
Let's test without going to hit run here
You'll notice you may either get drive already mounted
If you are attempting to mount the Google Drive
Second time
Because you won't have to mount it twice in the same project
But if you haven't yet mounted Google Drive and you'll need this line to authenticate
Google colab
Another time
But you already got it for this project then
You'll get the message that the drive has already been mounted
It just means that this line was written a second time
That's because I already called this line in my project
Funtime
Did earlier
Announcer that you'll notice we have printed these value be
That's because that is the value asked to beat one cell
Inside of our third sheet
This means that we successfully were able to pull a value from
Our file
You'll recall into exigo
We populated the third sheet with
The names of the column
Hid one and I hit run
I'm going to see deep being printed out
That's because
I populated my sheet with the names
The column letters in a certain range
Some will be out of range switches Z1 if I had run I'll get none that's because I was out of range
You can go back a couple extras to see this or
Just use any file that you have on your computer or on Google Drive
And then it call one of its worksheets by name
Evan call one of the values in that cell
Compare that we have exactly that value at C1
For example let me go to that exact
New workbook in my Google Sheets
You can also open it on your computer and look at this this is a new workbook we created two actors ago
And that's also
The same exact style that we're accessing
You'll notice it has several worksheets it has new active workbook it has number two
Which has some value here
And it has third sheet
Which has the names of columns
Call letters in a certain range
And this is a sheet from which we pulled the values as we try to get Z busy without
Out of this range
This proves that we successfully managed to open up new workbook
Via open Pike cell programmatically
And we grabbed the third sheets
And pulled a value from one of its cells
And we did all that via open pie Excel
Congratulations to everyone
That is how you can read from a workbook
Programmatically via
Open pie Excel